Oliver Galt

Email: olivermgalt@gmail.com | Phone: +44 7751 191042

Summary:

Driven and adaptable MA graduate with a background in teaching, research, and cross-cultural negotiation and mediation. Independently acquired proficiency in both Python and quantitative analysis, demonstrating a growth mentality, a self-starter attitude, and a strong problem-solving aptitude. Extensive global travel experience,

Core Skills:

Proofreading & Research Training & Coaching Conflict Resolution

Creative & Technical Writing Public Speaking Statistical Analysis

Work Experience:

ESL Teacher, American Polytechnic College, Ho Chi Minh City

Nov 2023 - Present

Designed and taught lessons with a focus on phonetic exercises, phoneme theory, and interactive speaking activities, leading to student accent reduction and clarity of speech.

ESL Teacher, VUS, Ho Chi Minh City

Oct 2023 - Present

Utilised a blend of traditional and modern educational techniques, incorporating digital tools and interactive activities to facilitate a dynamic learning environment.

ESL Teacher, Concorde Intl, Canterbury

May - Sep 2022, May -

Aug 2023

Implemented an engaging curriculum for students of various age groups and proficiency levels, with a focus on vocabulary acquisition and cultural awareness.

Administrative Assistant, Aguere Nest Hostels, Tenerife

Oct – Dec 2021

Court Usher, Inner London Crown Court

Jan – July 2021

ESL teacher at Leon HQ

Aug - Dec 2019

Designed a syllabus and taught a weekly class for Leon kitchen staff.

ESL Teacher at Oxford International

June – Aug 2018

Designed and delivered language lessons for culturally diverse classes.

Education:

University of Kent, International Conflict Analysis, MA – 2:1

Sep 2022 - Aug 2023

Thesis: Pearson correlation analysis of grassroots disgust sentiment towards immigrant groups expressed online vs. racially and religiously motivated crimes, using Python.

Engaged in a series of professional development workshops and seminars, including **Cafe Diplomatico**, which emphasised advanced negotiation techniques, collaborative mediation, and the role of gender in peacebuilding.

Birkbeck, University of London, Philosophy, BA - 2:1

Oct 2018 - July 2021

Newcastle College, CELTA: English language teacher training

Feb – June 2018

Projects:

Currently training a large lanuage model to recognise disgust sentiment in online forums, in order to pursue research.

Active participation in Toastmasters International, honing communication and leadership skills.

Skilled and self-taught at piano, singing, and ukulele, having given performances with each.